Guide to the William Heyen Papers YCAL MSS 352
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- October 2015 Acquisition, 1915–2015; 27.22 Linear Feet (31 boxes)
  - Annotated Books
    - Gibbons, Robert. Traveling Companion, 2012 (Box 66)
      Signed by Gibbons. Contains drafts of a few scherzo, & of several prose pieces maybe for Pig Notes if expanded.
    - Gourevitch, Philip. We wish to inform you that tomorrow we will be killed with or families: Stories from Rwanda, 1998 (Box 66)
      Contains the 1st drafts of about 15 poems for The Orphanage—see back flyleaf for page #s.
    - Grunberg, Arnon. The Jewish Messiah, 2008 (Box 66)
      Contains about a dozen of the 13-syllable poems in 1st drafts.
    - Hardison, O.B. Disappearing Through the Skylight: Culture and Technology in the Twentieth Century, 1989 (Box 66)
      This book contains the first drafts of 6-8 of the 13-syllable poems that are going into the manuscript of The Orphanage.
    - Hart, William. Evil: A Primer, 2004 (Box 67)
      Contains the first drafts of "Guilt," "Etymological Plaint," "Before Rilke," & several scherzi.
    - Harth, Erich. Dawn of a Millennium: Beyond Evolution and Culture, 1990 (Box 67)
      Contains notes & scratching.
    - Hersey, John. Hiroshima, 1989 (Box 67)
      Reprint. This book contains the 1st drafts of three sections of my Hiroshima Suite.
    - Highwater, Jamake. Journey to the Sky, 1978 (Box 67)
      Contains drafts of a few of the 13-syllable poems.
    - Highwater, Jamake. The Language of Vision: Meditations on Myth and Metaphor, 1994 (Box 67)
      This book contains the drafts of a half-dozen poems that eventually appeared in magazines and/or my "Crazy Horse in Stillness" (1996). See back flyleaf.
    - Hilberg, Raul. The Politics of Memory: The Journey of a Holocaust Historian, 1996 (Box 67)
      This book contains the first drafts of the poems "The Berries" & "Museum Visitor Coda" that appear in Shoah Train: Poems.
    - Hirschfield, Brad. Ed. Remember for Life: Holocaust Survivors' Stories of Faith and Hope, 2007 (Box 67)
      Contains the first drafts of a half-dozen poems (see back cover for list).
    - Hughes, Ted. Letters of Ted Hughes, 2007 (Box 67)
      Ed. Christopher Reid. Contains 1st drafts of a half-dozen scherzo, & one other piece (204).
    - Kashner, Sam. When I was Cool: My Life at the Jack Kerouac School, 2004 (Box 67)
      Contains the first drafts of a half-dozen or so scherzo.
    - King, Matthew. Noble Red Man, 1994 (Box 67)
      Ed. Harvey Arden. This book contains the first drafts of a couple-three poems that did or didn't get into the Crazy Horse & the Custers: The River of Electricity manuscript.
    - Kis, Danilo. Homo Poeticus: Essays & Interviews, 1995 (Box 67)
      Contains the first drafts of 15-20 scherzi, & of 3-4 longer poems including "Chamber," "Heart," & "Life."
    - Klein, Gerda Weissmann. All But My Life, 1957 (Box 67)
      Inscribed by the author, & w. letters laid in. Contains 1st draft of two poems—one, "Milk Silhouette," ended up in "Erika."
    - Lansky, Aaron. Outwitting History: The Amazing Adventures of a Man Who Rescued a Million Yiddish Books, 2004 (Box 67)
      Contains the 1st drafts of a half-dozen poemlets that will go into The Orphanage, and first drafts of a few other poems that might turn out to be keepers.
    - Larson, Erik. In the Garden of Beasts: Love, Terror, and an American Family in Hitler's Berlin, 2011 (Box 68)
      Contains the first drafts of about a dozen scherzo + "Prophecy."
    - Leavy, Jane. The Last Boy: Mickey Mantle and the End of America's Childhood, 2010 (Box 68)
      This book contains the first drafts of about ten scherzo & one or three other things.
    - Lengyel, Olga. Five Chimneys, 1973 (Box 68)
      Annotated, & mentioned in notes for "Erika"/"The Candle."
    - Levi, Primo. A Tranquil Star, 2007 (Box 68)
      Contains the first draft of the prose piece "Exile Suite" on back flyleaves.
    - Levi, Primo. The Voice of Memory: Interviews, 1961-1987, 2001 (Box 68)
      Contains drafts of several scherzi.
    - Lilly, John C. The Center of the Cyclone: An Autobiography of Inner Space, 1972 (Box 68)
      Contains notes & queries from the time I was losing sleep over problems with Time Being Books & Brodsk y.
    - Lyle, Sparky. The Bronx Zoo, 1979 (Box 68)
      Contains drafts of several scherzo.
    - MacLeish, Archibald. Letters of Archibald MacLeish 1907-1982, 1983 (Box 68)
      Ed. R.H. Winnick. Materials laid in. "Contains the first draft of my poem "The New American Poetry" which appeared in TriQuarterly & then in "The Confessions of Doc Williams & Other Poems" (2006).
    - Mails, Thomas E. Fools Crow, 1979 (Box 68)
      Contains the 1st drafts of a couple poems that ended up in "Crazy Horse in Stillness" (1996).
    - Mamet, David. The Wicked Son: Anti-Semitism, Self-Hatred, and the Jews, 2006 (Box 68)
      This book contains the first drafts of several scherzo.
    - Mandelstam, Osip. Selected Poems, 1973 (Box 68)
      Trans. Brown & Merwin. Contains first drafts of "That which is Lost" & a poem for Han (p. 56) that could become a strong one?
    - Martel, Yann. Life of Pi, 2001 (Box 69)
      This book contains on its back leaves about a dozen of the poems that will go into The Orphanage.
    - Martin, Billy. Billyball, 1987 (Box 69)
      Drafts of a couple poems on p. 276, but they ain't much & probably won't help with "Yankees Suite."
    - Martin, Billy. Number 1, 1980 (Box 69)
      This book contains several stanzas toward what might or might not become a keeper.
    - McKibbon, William. The End of Nature, 1989 (Box 69)
    - McMurtry, Larry. Crazy Horse, 1999 (Box 69)
      This book contains the first drafts of about 8 poems that became part of the Crazy Horse & the Custers: The River of Electricity manuscript.
    - Milosz, Czeslaw. Road-side Dog, 1998 (Box 69)
      This book contains poems & prose pieces that have appeared or will appear in several of my books including Pig Notes & Dumb Music, The Rope, A Poetics of Hiroshima, & The Confessions of Doc Williams.
    - Miyazawa, Kenji. Spring & Asura, 1973 (Box 69)
      Trans. Hiroaki Sato. Contains the 1st drafts of two poems.
    - Monette, Paul. Borrowed Time: An AIDS Memoir, 1988 (Box 69)
      Contains the first draft of a poem that came to nothing.
    - Morgan, Charles H. George Bellows: Painter of America, 1965 (Box 69)
      Heavily annotated toward the Autumn Brook MAG broadside.
    - Nelson, Victoria. My Time in Hawaii: A Polynesian Memoir, 2003 (Box 69)
      Contains the first drafts of the poem "Leper Memory" that appeared in Chaminade Literary Review & then in The Rope (2003).
    - Newton, Isaac. New Theory about Light and Colors, 1965 (Box 69)
    - Noll, Richard. The Aryan Christ: The Secret Life of Carl Jung, 1997 (Box 69)
      Contains first drafts of a half-dozen poems that are to be published in Crazy Horse & the Custers: The River of Electricity, etc.
    - Oates, Joyce Carol. The Journal of Joyce Carol Oates 1973-1982, 2007 (Box 69)
      This is an advance uncorrected proof of this journal that is dedicated: "for Gail Godwin, and for Bill Heyen—fellow explorers of the landscape within." Very heavily annotated.
    - O'Donnell, James P. The Berlin Bunker, 1979 (Box 70)
      Bought in London, read in 1981—back flyleaf has the start of a poem.
    - Oh, Sadaharu. A Zen Way of Baseball, 1984 (Box 70)
      Contains notes toward "Oh Joy" published long ago by Ewert and then published in The Football Corporations (2012).
    - Patterson, David. Along the Edge of Annihilation: the Collapse and Recovery of Life in the Holocaust Diary, 1999 (Box 70)
      Contains first drafts of the "Shekhinah/Scorpion" poem, "Sailing to Danzig," "Prayer," "Definition," & of several of the 13-syllable poems for The Orphanage.
    - Patterson, Rebecca. The Riddle of Emily Dickinson, 1951 (Box 70)
      Annotations & see back flyleaf.
    - Philbrick, Nathaniel. Mayflower, 2006 (Box 70)
      Contains 1st draft of "Covenant" (34) & of 5-10 scherzi.
    - Rees, Laurence. Auschwitz: The Nazis & the 'Final Solution', 2005 (Box 70)
      Contains the first drafts of "Cubist Crematorium" [became "Determination" in The Candle], "Benediction," "Lucille Eichengreen," & a few of the scherzi.
    - Reynolds, David S. Walt Whitman, 2005 (Box 70)
      Contains the first drafts of "Free Verse" & "Hydra" & a poem (p. 35) that might have become "The Hens." And one scherzo.
    - Rich, Adrienne. What Is Found There: Notebooks on Poetry and Politics, 1993 (Box 70)
      Read April-May 2012—my annotations.
    - Rosenblum, Joe. Defy the Darkness: A Tale of Courage in the Shadow of Mengele, 2001 (Box 70)
      Contains the first drafts of several poems including "Joe Rosenblum: Parable," "Joe Rosenblum: The Maggots," & "Dream."
    - Sartre, Jean-Paul. The Words: The Autobiography, 1964 (Box 71)
      Contains the drafts of 6-8 scherzi.
    - Scarry, Elaine. On Beauty and Being Just, 1999 (Box 71)
      Contains the first draft of "Truth" & of several scherzo.
    - Scott, Nathan A. The Wild Prayer of Longing: Poetry and the Sacred, 1971 (Box 71)
      Reviewed for Saturday Review in 1971. Heavily annotated.
    - Secrest, Meryle. Shoot the Widow: Adventures of a biographer in Search of Her Subject, 2007 (Box 71)
      Contains the first draft of "Nocturne"—p. 153--& of about 15 scherzi.
    - Sereny, Gita. Albert Speer: His Battle with Truth, 1995 (Box 71)
      This book contains first drafts of several poems including "Time Map," "R: Architecture," "Hitler Hears of Himmler's Betrayal," "Context," "Poem Ending in Trite Rhyme," Vollzug," etc.
    - Silko, Leslie Marmon. Ceremony, 1986 (Box 71)
      Contains the first couple drafts of a poem that went into "Crazy Horse in Stillness" (1996). Notes laid in.
    - Simpson, Louis. The Poet's Theme, 1988 (Box 71)
    - Smokler, Kevin. Ed. Bookmark Now: Writing in the Age of Information Overload, 2005 (Box 71)
      The back flyleaf of this book contains the first draft of one of the sections of "The Green Bookcase" essay & book.
    - Soik, Helmut Maria. Rimbaud under the Steel Helmet, 1976 (Box 71)
      Contains the draft of an abandoned poem called "Depression."
    - Stone, Richard. Mammoth: The Resurrection of an Ice Age Giant, 2001 (Box 71)
      Contains the drafts of a couple scherzi & of a poem called "Siberia" that came to nothing.
    - Szapszewicz, Maria. For the People I Love and Can't Forget: Poems and Memories of the Holocaust, 2006 (Box 71)
      Holds a few notes, & the draft of one scherzo. I write about this book in my journal (1/5-6/12).
    - Szpilman, Wladyslaw. The Pianist, 1999 (Box 71)
      Contains the first draft of a poem called "Music," & of one or two other things.
    - Theroux, Phyllis. The Journal Keeper: A Memoir, 2010 (Box 71)
      Contains the chainsaw poem "Sentence," the scherzo "Lion Tamer," maybe a couple false starts. I plan to speak of this trying book in my essay on journaling…. Read at Chautauqua 8/11/11…. Also contains "Time."
    - Van der Post, Laurens. Feather Fall, 1994 (Box 72)
      This book contains the first drafts of about thirty poems that became part of my Diana, Charles, & the Queen (1998—BOA Editions). The back flyleaf contains a list.
    - Knyz︠h︡kovyĭ znak shestydesi︠a︡tnykiv / [vsupna statti︠a︡ i upori︠a︡dkuvanni︠a︡ Mykola Viruk], 1972 (Box 72)
      So. Bound Brook, N. J.: V-vo Sv. Sofiï, 1972.
    - Waite, Robert G. L. The Psychopathic God: Adolf Hitler, 1977 (Box 72)
      I must have been reading this book when I was writing "Poem Touching the Gestapo."
    - Warren, Robert Penn. Robert Penn Warren Talking: Interviews 1950-1978, 1980 (Box 72)
      Ed. Watkins & Hiers. Annotated, and contains the draft of a quatrain (p. 304) that never went anywhere.
    - Weiss, Moshe. From Oswiecim to Auschwitz: Poland Revisited, 1994 (Box 72)
      Contains 1st drafts of several poems including "Synagogue Elegy," "Target," "On the Way Home," "Poland Village Elegy," & "Orchard Sonnet," & "Meditation in Oak."
    - Welch, James. Fool's Crow, 1986 (Box 72)
      This book contains 1st drafts of several poems that went into "Crazy Horse in Stillness." Also, several pages of Heyen notes laid in.
    - West Hills Review: A Walt Whitman Journal, 1979 (Box 72)
      This is the first issue (Fall 1979) of this journal, contains a Heyen memoir and holograph additions to it, and a page of manuscript laid in. His full memoir of Long Island appears in Home: Autobiographies (2004).
    - Wiesel, Elie. Conversations with Elie Wiesel, 2001 (Box 72)
      Contains the first drafts of a couple of (maybe) Pig Notes.
    - Wiesenthal, Simon. The Murderers Among Us, 1967 (Box 72)
      Read in 1980—background for poems.
    - Williams, William Carlos. Selected Poems, 1985 (Box 72)
      Ed. Charles Tomlinson (reprint c. 1985). Contains the drafts of several 1993 poems I never did anything with.
    - Winemaker, Susan. Concertina: An Erotic Memoir of Extravagant Tastes and Extreme Desires, 2007 (Box 72)
      Contains 1st drafts of the poems "Soft Touch" and "Orgasm," & a couple other things (the scherzo "In Memory of Archie").
    - Wright, James. Moments of the Italian Summer, 1976 (Box 72)
      Heavily annotated.
  - Personal and Financial Papers
    This subseries includes financial records, contracts, memorabilia, and other personal papers.
    - BOA royalties, 1997–2009 (Box 73)
    - Carnegie-Mellon (Gerry Costanza), 2010 (Box 73)
    - Crazy Horse royalty, 1996–2008 (Box 73)
    - Fairchild Award, 1996 (Box 73)
    - Guggenheim application, 1976–1978 (Box 73)
    - Heyen coat of arms, 1972 (Box 73)
    - Heyen jersey, undated (Box 74)
    - Memory notes, 2004–2009 (Box 75)
    - NEA, 1974–1997 (Box 75)
    - Personal papers, 1996–2013 (Box 75)
    - Royalties Noise, 1976–1988 (Box 75)
    - Royalties Vic, 1987–1994 (Box 75)
    - Royalty, 1975–2010 (Box 75)
    - Royalty CR, 1986–1992 (Box 75)
    - Royalty Erika, 1986–2004 (Box 75)
    - Royalty Swastika, 1978–1989 (Box 75)
    - TBB, 1992–2008 (Box 75)
    - Timeless Press publishing agreements, 1990–1991; 3 Folders (Box 75)
    - Vanguard royalties, 1980–1989 (Box 75)
  - Audiovisual and Computer Media
    This subseries contains audio and video recordings of interviews, readings and events, and musical works co-created by William Heyen. Electronic copies of Heyen's writings are also included.
    Arranged under two subheadings: Audiovisual Media and Computer Media.
    - Audiovisual Media
      - Buffalo State presents William Heyen, undated (Box 76)
      - Cruises 2003, 2005 (Box 76)
      - Cruise 2003 Royal Caribbean (Box 76)
      - Erika, 1991 (Box 76)
      - Falling From Heaven, 1991 (Box 76)
      - Hall of Fame induction SUNY Brockport, undated (Box 76)
      - Hannelore and Bill in Germany/ Margret and Hans in Amerika, undated (Box 76)
      - Host, 1995 (Box 76)
      - Krause tape: May 2000 visit, 2000 May (Box 76)
      - Kristen. Bill Heyen copy. 1985 S.H. college. (Box 76)
      - Kristen and Stephen, 1991 August 3 (Box 76)
      - Letter to Bill, 1982 (Box 76)
      - Phil Brady Poetry Reading: William Heyen, 2001 (Box 76)
      - Poetry Workshop Visits an Old Barn, 1987 (Box 76)
      - Pterodactyl Rose, 1991 (Box 77)
      - Ribbons the Gulf War, 1991 (Box 77)
      - Terre and Bill, 1990 July 14 (Box 77)
    - Computer Media
      - Computer media, 2003–2009 (Box 78)
      - Computer media, 2003-2009 (Box 79)
- June 2021 Acquisition, circa 2006 December; .25 Linear Feet (1 box)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from William Heyen on the George B. Alvord Fund, 2021.
  - Notebooks containing "Scherzi" poems, circa 2006 December (Box 45)
    A collection of one hundred or more thirteen-syllable poems written in four, small notebooks contained in a slipcase. The origins of some of the poems are noted.
- August 2022 Acquisition, 2018-2020; 0.21 Linear Feet 1 box
  Purchased with the George B. Alvord Fund, 2022.
  This accession contains writings and other materials created by or related to the life and work of William Heyen.
  - Burbs, circa 2018-2019 (Box 80)
  - Cleavage & what love might come to mean Comedy, undated (Box 80)
  - Nazi patrol, circa 2020, undated; 3 Folders (Box 80)
  - Sator, undated (Box 80)
  - Torch song, circa 2020 (Box 80)
- February 2023 Acquisition, 1937-2022; 12.76 Linear Feet 35 boxes
  Box 114 (born digital): Restricted fragile. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Purchased with the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund and the George B. Alvord Fund, 2023.
  Materials in this accession are organized into five series: I. Correspondence, 1982 - 2021. II. Writings, 1970 - 2022. III. Professional papers, 1972 - 2017. IV. Personal papers, 1937 - 2020. V. Computer media, undated.
  - Correspondence, 1982-2021; 4.08 Linear Feet (11 boxes)
    - "A" general, 2009-2019 (Box 81)
    - Benson, Warren, 2000; undated (Box 81)
    - Brady, Philip, 2010-2012 (Box 81)
    - "B" general, 1999-2021; 6 Folders (Box 81)
    - Cotter, Craig, 2015-2021; 3 Folders (Box 81)
    - Cotter, Craig, 2016-2021; 6 Folders (Box 82)
    - "C" general, 2015-2019; 3 Folders (Box 82)
    - "D" general, 2009-2021; 3 Folders (Box 82)
    - Ewert, William B., 2001 (Box 83)
    - Etruscan Press, 2004-2007 (Box 83)
    - "E" general, 1999-2021; 2 Folders (Box 83)
    - "F" general, 2007; 2014 (Box 83)
    - "G" general, 2001-2021; 6 Folders (Box 84)
    - Heyen-abortion, 1989 (Box 84)
    - Howe, Oscar, undated (Box 84)
    - "H" general, 2020-2021; 2 Folders (Box 84)
    - "H" general, 2003-2020; 3 Folders (Box 85)
    - Jantz, Suzan, 2008-2010 (Box 85)
    - "J" general, 1982; 2018-2019 (Box 85)
    - "K" general, 2014-2020; 2 Folders (Box 85)
    - "L" general, 2012-2021 (Box 85)
    - "M" general, 2009-2021 (Box 85)
    - "Mc" general, 2014-2020 (Box 85)
    - "N" general, 2014-2021 (Box 85)
    - "O" general, 2018-2019 (Box 85)
    - Pentagram Press, 1996 (Box 86)
    - "P" general, 2001-2020 (Box 86)
    - "Q" general, 2016-2021 (Box 86)
    - Reed, Ishmael, 1983; undated (Box 86)
    - "R" general, 1984 (Box 86)
    - "S" general, 1988-2021 (Box 86)
    - Tart, Indrek, 1991-1994 (Box 86)
    - "T" general, 2015; 2019 (Box 86)
    - Vinci, Tony, 2002-2003 (Box 86)
    - "V" general, 2017-2021 (Box 86)
    - "W" general, 2014-2021 (Box 86)
    - "Z" general, 2014; 2016 (Box 86)
    - Barkan/CCC correspondence, 2015-2016 (Box 87)
    - Barkan, Stan, 2016-2019; undated; 5 Folders (Box 87)
    - Broomfield, Michael, 2014-2021; 4 Folders (Box 87)
    - Belgium/Dirk Blockreel, 2001 (Box 87)
    - Class of 1961, 2004 (Box 87)
    - Cruise: Class of '61, 2001 (Box 87)
    - Gibbons, Robert, 2021 September 30 (Box 88)
    - Howling Dog Press, 2007 (Box 88)
    - Lehman, David, 1996 (Box 88)
    - NPR, 2002 (Box 88)
    - Olimpia, Iacob, 2016 (Box 86)
    - Silko, Leslie Marmon, 2015-2021; undated; 3 Folders (Box 88)
    - Correspondence, 1986-2016; 11 Folders (Box 89)
    - Correspondence, 1968-2019; 12 Folders (Box 90)
    - Correspondence, 2001-2021; 7 Folders (Box 91)
  - Writings, 1970-2022; 8.33 Linear Feet (17 boxes)
    - After sun knowledge 5, 2019-2020 (Box 92)
    - And devil says, 2007 November 11 (Box 92)
    - Baseball/Yankee suite, 2012 (Box 92)
    - Beyond violining: things, undated (Box 92)
    - Call me snake poems, 2021 May 16 (Box 92)
    - Candle collected & new poems 1970-2015 fragment, 2011 October 3 (Box 92)
    - Candle: collected Holocaust poems, undated (Box 92)
    - Candle, undated (Box 92)
    - Candle: review by John Doser, 2017 January 8 (Box 92)
    - Chainsaw poems, 2014-2015; 3 Folders (Box 92)
    - Chainsaw rejects, 2014; undated (Box 92)
    - Devil's song, 2005 (Box 92)
    - Don. Copy 2 of 3 copies, 2019 November 4 (Box 93)
    - Don. #5 of 5 copies, 2019 November 8 (Box 93)
    - Don: 40 plays, 2019 November 4 (Box 93)
    - Don. A play in six lines, 2019 November 15 (Box 93)
    - Elegy: Karin Helene Jordan, undated (Box 94)
    - Index cards, undated (Box 96)
    - Index cards, undated (Box 97)
    - Index cards, undated (Box 98)
    - Journal considerations, 2006; 2017 (Box 94)
    - Journal, 2006-2008; 3 Folders (Box 94)
      These files contain numbers 44, 45, and 46.
    - Journal, 2008-2009; 2 Folders (Box 95)
      These files contain numbers 47 and 48.
    - Lists for Pig Notes, undated (Box 95)
    - MAG, 2013 October 8 (Box 95)
    - M[?]rable matter, undated (Box 95)
    - MSS for Poemlet Press, 2013; undated; 2 Folders (Box 95)
    - MSS for Poemlet Press, 2011-2016; 4 Folders (Box 99)
    - Misc. poems mss, notes, etc., 2000; undated (Box 99)
    - My mother-poems/essay, 2007 (Box 99)
    - Nature, 2019 (Box 99)
    - Nature selected and new poems, 1970-2020; undated (Box 99)
    - Notebook, 2002-2011; undated; 6 Folders (Box 99)
    - Notes, undated; 3 Folders (Box 100)
    - Oates Chautauqua talks, 2000 (Box 100)
    - 1 On reading this book 2 Covenant 3 Crop Circles, 2016-2020 (Box 100)
    - Orioles, 2005 May 6 (Box 100)
    - Orphanage, 2005-2008; 5 Folders (Box 100)
    - Orphanage, 2008 June 3 (Box 101)
    - Painted clock, undated (Box 101)
    - Poems, 1978-2017; 6 Folders (Box 101)
    - Poems, 2017-2021; 6 Folders (Box 102)
    - Poems and notes, 2003-2010; undated; 4 Folders (Box 102)
    - Poems and notes, 2003-2016; 11 Folders (Box 103)
    - Poems and notes, 2014-2019; 2 Folders (Box 104)
    - Poems in progress, 1989 April (Box 104)
    - Prose: an essay on form, undated (Box 104)
    - Prose to send out, undated (Box 104)
    - Return, 1970 (Box 104)
    - Scherzo project, 2019-2022; 2 Folders (Box 104)
    - Selected poems, 1970-2020; undated; 2 Folders (Box 104)
    - Sunlight (Holocaust essay), 2005 July 5; undated (Box 104)
    - Trees an autobiography ribbons, undated (Box 104)
    - Various poems toward the football corporation, 2005; undated (Box 104)
    - What love might come to mean, 2015-2020 (Box 104)
    - Yu, Paul: Music a poem on the occasion of the investiture of Dr. Paul M. Yu as fifth president of SUNY College at Brockport, 1998-1999 (Box 104)
    - Writings, 2016-2020; 3 Folders (Box 105)
    - Writings of others
      - Atkinson, Michael: Poems, undated (Box 106)
      - Beaudin, Michael: Life list, 2019 (Box 106)
      - Bobrow, Laura T.: Betrayed, undated (Box 106)
      - Botsford, Alan: Possessions poems in American poetry, 2020 September 3 (Box 106)
      - Brady, Philip: Phantom signs a life in Universe City, 2017 (Box 106)
      - Brady, Philip: To banquet with the worthy Ethiopians, 2012 June 16 (Box 106)
      - Cross-cultural communications, 2015-2016; 3 Folders (Box 106)
      - Dougherty, Edward A.: Grace Street, 2015 October 14 (Box 106)
      - Dzwonkoski, Peter: Wit and Wisdom of Cass, 2005 (Box 106)
      - Fuentes, James: Horrors of the voiceless, undated (Box 106)
      - Gregorek, Aniela and Jerzy: Native foreigners Polish-Jewish poetry between the World Wars, 2015 (Box 107)
      - Jospé, Kitty: Sum: 1, 2020 July 7 (Box 107)
      - Kerman, Judith: Postcards from America, 2015 July 21 (Box 107)
      - Lynch, Grace, 2104; 4 Folders (Box 107)
      - Merrifield, Karla Lynn: Psyche's scroll-a poem, 2018 February 3 (Box 107)
      - Nusbaum, Susan: Divorski: Open wide, the eye, 2015 (Box 107)
      - Prager, June: Distant survivors based on poetry by William Heyen, 2016 July 12-2016 July 13 (Box 107)
      - Prajitura, Gabriel + Staryk: online pubs, 2007 (Box 107)
      - Seaver, Edwina: Heyen's Whitman, 2018 May 23 (Box 107)
      - Silko, Leslie Marmon: artwork, 2008; 2019-2020 (Box 107)
      - Silko, Leslie Marmon: Chapulin's portrait, undated (Box 107)
      - Silko, Leslie Marmon: Ocean story, 2007 (Box 107)
      - Silko, Leslie Marmon: Rain book, 2021 (Box 107)
      - Sobieraj, Tomasz Marek: Poems, 2018 September 30 (Box 107)